Redwood Canyon Ramblers collection
American Folklife Center, Library of Congress
Redwood Canyon Ramblers collection 1959-2013
AFC 2011/011
Rosenberg, Neil V.
approximately 3134 items
9 sound tape reels: analog, 7 1/2 ips 2 track; 7 in.
1 sound tape reel: analog; 5 in.
6 sound cassettes: analog
2843 sound files (AIF, MP3, WAV): digital
2 videocassettes (VHS): sound, color; 1/2 in.
10 video files (IMG, MOV): digital
52 photographs: digital, black and white, color, BMP, JPG, PDF
161 document files (DOC, DOCX, JPG, PDF, TXT): digital
approximately 50 sheets
American Folklife Center, Library of Congress Washington, D.C.
Collection of audio and video studio recordings, demo/audition tapes, live recordings at various clubs, coffeehouses, and auditoriums; jam sessions; and radio programs featuring the Redwood Canyon Ramblers, including a show from Radio Kansai, Kobe, Hyogo, Japan (1991).
Provenance
Neil Rosenberg; Brian Miksis; Mayne Smith; Donation; 2011, 2014.
Accruals
Accruals were received in 2014 and 2019. Future accruals are expected.
Related Material
Neil V. Rosenberg bluegrass music collection (AFC 2002/009)
Access and Restrictions
The Redwood Canyon Ramblers collection is open to research. To request materials, please contact the Folklife Reading Room at https://hdl.loc.gov/loc.afc/folklife.contact
Certain restrictions to use or copying of materials may apply.
Alternate Formats
Many recordings in the Redwood Canyon Ramblers collection exist in both analog and digitized formats. Digitized versions were created by donor Brian Miksis as part of his "Redwood Canyon Ramblers Archive" digital project. Miksis edited them to enhance quality, and he created derivatives: Video files are available in Final Cut Pro output (mov) and DVD disk image (img) versions. Audio files are available in high-resolution (aif or wav), medium-resolution CD pre-tagged (aif), and low-resolution mp3 pre-tagged (mp3) versions. Analog, high-resolution digital audio, and FCP digital video are listed in detail throughout Series 2: Event recordings and related materials. Medium and lower resolution digital audio, and DVD digital video, are listed in Additional digital surrogates of selected recordings in Series 2.
Biographical Note
Neil V. Rosenberg
Neil V. Rosenberg (born 1939, in Seattle, Washington), grew up in Olympia, Washington, Los Alamos, New Mexico, and Berkeley, California. From age seven he studied violin, and later studied guitar and voice. His studies at Oberlin College (where he earned a B.A. in history) overlapped with his time as co-founder of the Redwood Canyon Ramblers. After graduation from Oberlin he attended Indiana University (where he earned his M.A. and Ph.D. degrees in folklore). Throughout this time he remained active as a musician and, with the banjo as his primary musical instrument, he played at the Brown County Jamboree in the early 1960s. His writing career from the mid-1960s has focused on bluegrass music history, and he has written critically acclaimed books including Bluegrass: A History (1985; revised 2005), Bluegrass Odyssey: A Documentary in Pictures and Words, 1966-86 (2001), and Bluegrass Generation: A Memoir (2018), as well as album liner notes and scholarly articles. His teaching career includes work at Indiana University (1966-1968) and Memorial University of Newfoundland (1968-2004). In Canada, as in the U.S., Rosenberg developed, founded, and mentored various musical endeavors: co-founder of the bluegrass band Crooked Stovepipe; host of a weekly bluegrass music show (broadcast on radio station CKIX-FM (St. John's, Newfoundland and Labrador, Canada); and numerous other achievements that served to draw and maintain a lively interest in the genre and history of bluegrass music. In 2014, he was inducted into the Bluegrass Hall of Fame.
Mayne Smith
Mayne Smith is a bluegrass musician, original member of the Redwood Canyon Ramblers, and author of the essay An Introduction to Bluegrass (1965).
Brian Miksis
Brian Miksis, a sound mixer with over 15 years of experience, digitized the recordings in this collection, and provided detailed metadata on the process and result. He has co-researched and produced an early history of Jerry Garcia's bluegrass roots, entitled Before the Dead (2018), and authored "An introduction to the Redwood Canyon Ramblers Archive".
Scope and Content
Collection of audio and video studio recordings, demo/audition tapes, live recordings at various clubs, coffeehouses, and auditoriums; jam sessions; and radio programs featuring the Redwood Canyon Ramblers, including a show from Radio Kansai, Kobe, Hyogo, Japan (1991).
The audio and video event recordings are on 18 analog recording tapes and over 59 digitized recordings. Analog recordings were collected by Neil Rosenberg. Digitized recordings were created by Brian Miksis from various source tapes. He cleaned, edited, and cut recordings into tracks, and he assembled them with digitized photographs and documentation as the "Redwood Canyon Ramblers Archive." The video files are available in Final Cut Pro output (mov) and DVD disk image (img) versions. The audio files are available in high-resolution (aif or wav), medium-resolution CD pre-tagged (aif), and low-resolution mp3 pre-tagged (mp3) versions.
Arrangement
The Redwood Canyon Ramblers collection is organized in 3 series:
Series 1. Inventories and writings
Series 2. Event recordings and related materials
Series 3. Photographic materials
Materials acquired in accruals sometimes duplicate materials in the original acquisition. Each recording session has been assigned an "Event ID" under which all recording versions of the same event are grouped, with related documentation. Events are arranged chronologically.
Filepaths and digital files can be found in afc2011011_dc001. Please see the AFC reference staff for access.
Selected Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the LC Catalog. They are grouped by name of person or organization, by subject or location, and by occupation and listed alphabetically.
People
Bebring, Tom; Berg, Pete, 1940-; Berline, Byron; Hambly, Scott; Mitsui, Tōru, 1940-2023; Monroe, Bill, 1911-1996; Neff, Ed, 1946-; Rosenberg, Neil V.; Rothman, Sandy; Smith, Mayne
Organizations
Blue Grass Boys; Carroll County Country Boys; Redwood Canyon Ramblers
Subjects
Bluegrass music--California.; Bluegrass music--Japan.; Country music.
Places
Berkeley (Calif.), event place.; Hamamatsu-shi (Japan), event place.; Los Angeles (Calif.), event place.
Form/Genre
Country music radio programs.; Manuscripts.; Sound recordings.; Videocassettes.
Container List
- Series 1: Inventories and writings
  Writings about the content and background of the "Redwood Canyon Ramblers Archive" digitization project, in addition to published articles about the musical journey of the band.
  Arranged chronologically, within two groups: documents created by Brian Miksis, followed by published articles.
  - "An introduction to the Redwood Canyon Ramblers Archive," by Brian Miksis, June 13, 2013, RCR Archive Introduction.pdf; 1 manuscript: black and white, digital (.pdf)
  - Song lists and personnel for all recordings in the Redwood Canyon Ramblers Archive, circa 2013, RCR Archive Chronological Index.pdf; 1 manuscript: black and white, digital (.pdf)
    Each event (except SR54 ) is described in this document. Brian Miksis compiled the information based on documentation that accompanied the recordings, his own research, observations while digitizing the recordings, and guidance from Neil Rosenberg (e.g., when the pitch needed adjustment to restore the audio quality). This document includes the names of the musicians, instruments played, the source recording history, the name and address of the recording location, and technical metadata regarding digitization.
  - "An Introduction to Bluegrass," by L. Mayne Smith, 1965, Bluegrass Messengers - An Introduction to Bluegrass- Smith 1965 JOAFL.pdf; 1 manuscript: color, digital (.pdf)
  - Magazine article about the Redwood Canyon Ramblers (in Japanese), April 1991, Moonshiner 4-91 pp 1_3-4.pdf, Moonshiner 4-91 pp 10-13.pdf, Moonshiner 4-91 pp 32-33.pdf; 3 manuscripts: black and white, digital (.pdf)
  - Magazine article about the Redwood Canyon Ramblers (in Japanese), May 1991, Moonshiner 5-91 pp 1-5.pdf; 1 manuscript: black and white, digital (.pdf)
  - "Rambling in Redwood Canyon: The Routes of Bluegrass," by Sandy Rothman, May-August 1991, Rothman RCR BU 1.pdf, Rothman RCR BU 2.pdf, Rothman RCR BU 3.pdf, Rothman RCR BU 4.pdf; 4 manuscripts: black and white, digital (.pdf)
  - "George Lyon talks to Neil Rosenberg," May 2001, 2001-05_canadian-folk-music-bulletin.pdf; 1 manuscript: black and white, digital (.pdf)
- Series 2: Event recordings and related materials
  Sound and moving image recordings of studio sessions and performances, with related documentation. See "Song lists and personnel for all recordings in the Redwood Canyon Ramblers Archive" for source/copy information.
  Arranged chronologically with Event IDs assigned by AFC. Recordings are sound-only for "SR" Event IDs and primarily video with sound for "MV" Event IDs.
  The high-resolution audio files (24bit/96kHz .aif or .wav) and Final Cut Pro output video files (mov) listed below are very large and best suited to archival and media uses. For basic listening and reference please consult lower-resolution versions at the end of this series.
  - Royal Recording Studio session, Berkeley, California - Neil Rosenberg, February 27, 1956, AFC 2011/011: SR17
    - Sound recording (cut-level), nvr1956-02-27t01.aif - nvr1956-02-27t07.aif; 7 sound files: high-resolution files, digital (.aif)
      "Sea Fever" 00:02:36
      "Lama In Tibet" 00:01:03
      "Isabelle" 00:01:57
      "Old West Chop" 00:01:47
      "Foreigners" 00:01:57
      "Eddystone Light" 00:01:05
      "Foggy Flats Blues" 00:02:25
    - Song list and production notes for SR17, June 20, 2011, nvr1956-02-27.txt; 1 manuscript: black and white, digital (.txt)
      Includes a list of the musicians, the source recording history, the name and address of the recording location, and technical information regarding digitization.
  - Hambly basement jam session, Berkeley, California, May 1956, AFC 2011/011: SR18
    - Sound recording (cut-level), rcr1956-05-00t01.wav - rcr1956-05-00t09.wav; 9 sound files: high-resolution files (.wav)
      "Piano and Drums Blues In C" 00:03:04
      "Fast Blues Jam In G" 00:07:23
      "Boogie Blues Jam In C" 00:04:26
      "When The Saints Go Marching In" 00:05:10
      "Modern Piano In C" 00:02:26
      "St. James Infirmary" 00:06:14
      "Drum Solo #1/That's The Way A Blast Should Be/Foggy Flats Blues" 00:02:51
      "Timber (Jerry The Mule)" 00:01:26
      "Drum Solo #2" 00:04:23
    - Song list and production notes for SR18, May 25, 2011, rcr1956-05-00.txt; 1 manuscript: black and white, digital (.txt)
  - Royal Recording Studio session, Berkeley, California - Scott Hambly, May 1956, AFC 2011/011: SR19
    - Sound recording (cut-level), sh1956-05-00.wav; 1 sound file: high-resolution file (.wav)
      "Frankie And Johnny" 00:06:37
    - Song list and production notes for SR19, May 25, 2011, sh1956-05-00.txt; 1 manuscript: black and white, digital (.txt)
  - Royal Recording Studio session, Berkeley, California - Neil Rosenberg and Scott Hambly, June 22, 1957, AFC 2011/011: SR20
    - Sound recording (cut-level), nvrsh1957-06-22.wav; 1 sound file: high-resolution file (.wav)
      "Four-Guitar Blues" 00:05:38
    - Song list and production notes for SR20, May 25, 2011, nvrsh1957-06-22.txt; 1 manuscript: black and white, digital (.txt)
  - Gould's basement recording session, Toledo, Ohio - Neil Rosenberg and Mayne Smith, November 29, 1957, AFC 2011/011: SR21
    - Sound recording (cut-level), nvrms1957-11-29t01.wav - nvrms1957-11-29t17.wav; 17 sound files: high-resolution files, digital (.wav)
      "John Henry" 00:03:32
      "Hard, Ain't It Hard" 00:02:47
      "East Virginia" 00:02:59
      "Lord, Lord, Lord" 00:01:40
      "Tom Dooley" 00:02:17
      "Dr. Freud" 00:02:20
      "Midnight Special" 00:03:40
      "Troubled Is My Name" 00:03:07
      "Salty Dog" 00:02:34
      "Old Joe Clark" 00:01:58
      "Wayfaring Stranger" 00:03:28
      "Take A Whiff On Me" 00:02:12
      "Casey Jones" 00:02:11
      "Oh Freedom" 00:02:50
      "Loping Along" 00:00:24
      "The Logger Lover" 00:03:32
      "This Train" 00:02:30
    - Song list and production notes for SR21, June 20, 2011, nvrms1957-11-29.txt; 1 manuscript: black and white, digital (.txt)
  - Royal Recording Studio session, Berkeley, California - Redwood Canyon Ramblers, August 27, 1958, AFC 2011/011: SR22
    - Sound recording (cut-level), rcr1958-08-27t01.wav - rcr1958-08-27t07.wav; 7 sound files: high-resolution files, digital (.wav)
      "Henry Martin" 00:03:53
      "Backwater Blues" 00:04:06
      "Titanic" 00:05:13
      "Rock Me Baby" 00:03:16
      "Little Maggie" 00:02:59
      "Jesse James" 00:04:21
      "Pay Me My Money Down" 00:02:36
    - Song list and production notes for SR22, December 12, 2012, rcr1958-08-27.txt; 1 manuscript: black and white, digital (.txt)
  - Royal Recording Studio session, Berkeley, California - Scott Hambly and Pete Berg, February 6, 1959, AFC 2011/011: SR24
    - Sound recording (cut-level), shpb1959-02-06t01.aif - shpb1959-02-06t07.aif; 7 sound files: high-resolution files, digital (.aif)
      "I Know How To Do It" 00:02:42
      "Ella Speed" 00:02:15
      Medley: "Wildwood Flower"/"Rosewood Casket"/"Cindy"/"Woody's Rag" 00:02:33
      "Banks Of The Ohio" 00:02:52
      "Molly And Tenbrooks" 00:01:57
      "Amelia Earhart" 00:02:33
      "Nooky Blues" 00:03:54
    - Song list and production notes for SR24, March 27, 2011, shpb1959-02-06.txt; 1 manuscript: black and white, digital (.txt)
    - "Nooky Blues," undated, Scott Hamblys Nooky Blues KRE.doc; 1 manuscript: black and white, digital (.doc)
      Lyrics for the song, plus technical metadata about the recording and the guitar, etc.
    - Scott reminisces about the mandolin, undated, Scotts notes 2-6-59.txt; 1 manuscript: black and white, digital (.txt)
      First-person reminiscence by Scott Hambly about the mandolin.
    - Original tape box, with handwritten notes, undated, shpb1959-02-06.pdf; 1 manuscript: black and white, digital (.pdf)
  - Redwood Canyon Ramblers at Berkeley Hillel, Berkeley, California, July 26, 1959, AFC 2011/011: SR25
    - Sound recording (cut-level), rcr1959-07-26t01.aif - rcr1959-07-26t14.aif; 14 sound files: high-resolution files, digital (.aif)
      "Hand Me Down My Walking Cane" - Janet Smith and Tom Barton 00:03:18
      "Roll In My Sweet Baby's Arms" - Redwood Canyon Ramblers 00:02:45
      "Mary Hamilton" - Tom Barton 00:04:50
      "Sweet Kate" - Janet Smith and Rita Weill 00:00:43
      Unidentified folk song - Janet Smith 00:01:22
      "Salty Dog" - Redwood Canyon Ramblers 00:02:10
      "Reuben" - Redwood Canyon Ramblers 00:02:04
      "The Cruel Mother" - Janet Smith 00:01:57
      "Gypsy Lady" - Janet Smith and Tom Barton 00:04:03
      "Red Apple Juice" - Redwood Canyon Ramblers 00:01:49
      "Dim Lights, Thick Smoke And Loud, Loud Music" - Redwood Canyon Ramblers 00:01:46
      "The Great Silkie" - Rita Weill 00:02:45
      "John Hardy" - Tom Barton 00:05:05
      "Israel Night Y'all Come" - unidentified female lead singer 00:01:35
    - Song list and production notes for SR25, July 4, 2011, rcr1959-07-26.txt; 1 manuscript: black and white, digital (.txt)
      From the documentation: "Tom [Barton] used this and Reel #26 in his collection to make Neil Rosenberg's Reel #203 compilation dub in 1973."
    - Handwritten set list, undated, rcr1959-07-26.pdf; 1 manuscript: black and white, digital (.pdf)
    - Original tape box, with handwritten notes, undated, rcr1959-07-25_26tapebox.pdf; 1 manuscript: black and white, digital (.pdf)
  - Redwood Canyon Ramblers at Northgate Club, Berkeley, California, July 28, 1959, AFC 2011/011: SR26
    - Sound recording (cut-level), rcr1959-07-28t01.aif - rcr1959-07-28t15.aif; 15 sound files: high-resolution files, digital (.aif)
      Set 1
      "How Mountain Girls Can Love" [fades in] 00:01:50
      "Little Maggie" 00:02:17
      "Amelia Earhart" 00:03:22
      "Honky Tonk Angels" 00:02:47
      "Reuben" 00:02:24
      "Salty Dog" (fades in) 00:02:36
      "Knoxville Girl" 00:04:21
      "Dim Lights, Thick Smoke And Loud, Loud Music" 00:02:36
      "Life Is Like A Mountain Railway" 00:02:32
      "Roll In My Sweet Baby's Arms" 00:01:05
      Set 2
      "A Million Years In Glory" 00:02:33
      "Foggy Mountain Chimes" 00:02:01
      "How Mountain Girls Can Love" 00:01:46
      "Roll In My Sweet Baby's Arms" [fades in] 00:01:45
      "Reuben" 00:02:19
    - Song list and production notes for SR26, July 5, 2011, rcr1959-07-28.txt; 1 manuscript: black and white, digital (.txt)
    - Handwritten set list, undated, rcr1959-07-28.pdf; 1 manuscript: black and white, digital (.pdf)
    - Original tape box, with handwritten notes, undated, rcr1959-07-28tapebox.pdf; 1 manuscript: black and white, digital (.pdf)
  - Home demo, Berkeley, California - Neil Rosenberg, July 30, 1959, AFC 2011/011: SR27
    - Sound recording (cut-level), nvr1959-07-30t01.aif - nvr1959-07-30t19.aif; 19 sound files: high-resolution files, digital (.aif)
      From the documentation: "excerpts from this were dubbed onto Neil Rosenberg's [tape] #203 in 1973."
      Neil's Intro/"My Name Is John Johanna" 00:04:03
      "Titanic" 00:04:56
      "Black Jack Davy" 00:02:50
      "Down In The Willow Garden" 00:01:05
      "Wildwood Flower"/"Freight Train"/"Oh Babe It Ain't No Lie" 00:02:26
      "Going Down The Road Feeling Bad"/talk about picking style and Peggy Seeger 00:02:13
      "Katy Cruel" 00:00:44
      "Railroad Bill" 00:01:50
      "Shule Aroo" 00:02:42
      "Blues In E" 00:04:12
      "Blues In D" 00:03:15
      "Nobody's Fault But Mine" 00:02:15
      "Old Blue" (fragment) [reel side change] 00:00:21
      "John Henry" 00:05:18
      "Gallow's Pole" 00:02:38
      "Ella Speed" 00:03:40
      "Working On The Railroad" 00:02:30
      "Skin Game Blues"/"God Loves His Children" (fragment on 12 string) 00:01:29
      "God Loves His Children" (on 6 string) 00:00:34
    - Song list and production notes for SR27, July 8, 2011, nvr1959-07-30.txt; 1 manuscript: black and white, digital (.txt)
    - Handwritten set list, undated, nvr1959-07-30.pdf; 1 manuscript: black and white, digital (.pdf)
    - Original tape box, with handwritten notes, undated, nvr1959-07-30 Tapebox.pdf; 1 manuscript: black and white, digital (.pdf)
  - Redwood Canyon Ramblers at The Northgate Restaurant, August 1959, AFC 2011/011: SR01
    - Sound recording (full), AFC 2011/011: SR01; RXJ 0530; 1 sound tape reel (acetate; Side 1: 00:46:39, Side 2: 00:41:05): analog, 7 1/2 ips, mono; 7 in.
      Recorded at The Northgate Restaurant, Berkeley, California. Original Rosenberg inventory number: tape 12.
    - Sound recording (cut-level), rcr1959-08-00t01.aif - rcr1959-08-00t30.aif; 30 sound files: high-resolution files, digital (.aif)
      "How Mountain Girls Can Love" [incomplete; this is the last part of the song] 00:00:52
      "Blue Ridge Cabin Home" 00:03:10
      "Pretty Polly" 00:03:01
      "Salty Dog" [with Tom Bebring on vocals] 00:02:31
      "Red Apple Juice (Sugar Baby)" 00:02:42
      "White House Blues" 00:03:01
      "Roll In My Sweet Baby's Arms" [with Tom Bebring on vocals] 00:03:13
      "Life's Railway To Heaven" 00:03:55
      "Mountain Fling" medley: "Wildwood Flower"/"Rosewood Casket"/"Cindy"/"Woody's Rag" 00:04:56
      "Jimmy Brown" 00:02:59
      "Wild Side Of Life" 00:04:44
      "Home Sweet Home" [instrumental]("better check the fiddle") 00:01:34
      Intermission/drumming/tuning [to 00:35:11] 00:02:41
      Set 3
      "Battleship of Maine" 00:03:16
      "Little Maggie" 00:03:48
      "Katy Dear" [with Tom Bebring on vocals] 00:02:47
      "Down The Road" [reel direction change] 00:01:49
      "Amelia Earhart" 00:03:52
      "Million Years In Glory" [with Tom Bebring on vocals] 00:03:17
      "Hard, Ain't It Hard" 00:02:13
      Intermission/drumming [to 00:11:23] 00:02:13
      Set 4
      "Your Love Is Like A Flower" [the beginning of the song is cut off] 00:03:29
      "Great Speckled Bird" 00:03:12
      "Knoxville Girl" [with Tom Bebring on vocals] 00:05:05
      "Randy Lynn Rag" 00:03:05
      "Bile Them Cabbage Down" [with Campbell Coe on guitar] 00:02:19
      "How Mountain Girls Can Love" 00:03:14
      "Dim Lights, Thick Smoke And Loud, Loud Music" ("big round of boos for our banjo player") 00:04:12
      "Pike County Breakdown" 00:03:20
      "Reuben's Train"/closing remarks 00:03:23
    - Song list and production notes for SR01, January 8, 2011, rcr1959-08-00.txt; 1 manuscript: black and white, digital (.txt)
    - Handwritten song list, with counter numbers from the tape deck, undated, rcr1959-08-00.pdf; 1 manuscript: black and white, digital (.pdf)
    - Neil V. Rosenberg in performance at Northgate, 1959, 590800 NVR at Northgate.jpg; 1 photograph: black and white, digital (.jpg)
  - KPFA demo audition, Berkeley, California - Redwood Canyon Ramblers, September 1959, AFC 2011/011: SR28
    - Sound recording (cut-level), rcr1959-09-00t01.aif - rcr1959-09-00t18.aif; 18 sound files: high-resolution files, digital (.aif)
      "Randy Lynn Rag" 00:02:04
      "How Mountain Girls Can Love" 00:02:10
      "Blue Ridge Mountain Home" 00:02:14
      "Million Years In Glory" [with Tom Bebring on vocals] 00:02:21
      "Roll In My Sweet Baby's Arms" [with Tom Bebring on vocals] 00:02:27
      "Little Maggie" 00:02:33
      "Pretty Polly" 00:02:25
      "White House Blues" 00:02:06
      "Hard, Ain't It Hard" 00:01:58
      "Home Sweet Home" 00:01:17
      Mountain Fling Medley: "Wildwood Flower"/"Rosewood Casket"/"Cindy"/"Woody's Rag" 00:03:57
      "Salty Dog" [with Tom Bebring on vocals] 00:02:08
      "Amelia Earhart" 00:03:19
      "Jimmie Brown" 00:02:17
      "Red Apple Juice (Sugar Baby)" 00:01:42
      "Pike County Breakdown" 00:02:08
      "Your Love Is Like A Flower" 00:02:28
      "How Mountain Girls Can Love" 00:02:15
    - Song list and production notes for SR28, April 19, 2011, rcr1959-09-00.txt; 1 manuscript: black and white, digital (.txt)
    - Handwritten song list, with counter numbers from the tape deck, undated, rcr1959_1960StudioSessions.pdf; 1 manuscript: black and white, digital (.pdf)
      Details about SR28 and SR29 are listed on the same document.
  - Royal Recording Studio session, Berkeley, California - Redwood Canyon Ramblers, December 26, 1959, AFC 2011/011: SR29
    - Sound recording (cut-level), rcr1959-12-26t01.aif - rcr1959-12-26t10.aif; 10 sound files: high-resolution files, digital (.aif)
      "Cripple Creek" 00:02:02
      "Darling Corey" #1 00:02:57
      "Darling Corey" #2 00:03:00
      "Pike County Breakdown" #1 00:02:05
      "Pike County Breakdown" #2 00:02:07
      "Winchester 94" 00:02:00
      "Mocking Banjo" #1 [breakdown] 00:01:51
      "Mocking Banjo" #2 00:02:38
      "Rocky Run" #1 [breakdown] 00:01:09
      "Rocky Run" #2 00:02:13
    - Song list and production notes for SR29, January 7, 2011, rcr1959-12-26.txt; 1 manuscript: black and white, digital (.txt)
    - Handwritten song list, with counter numbers from the tape deck, undated, rcr1959_1960StudioSessions.pdf; 1 manuscript: black and white, digital (.pdf)
      Details about SR28 and SR29 are in the same document.
  - Home demo love songs, Berkeley, California - Janet Smith, 1959, AFC 2011/011: SR23
    - Sound recording (cut-level), js1959t01.aif - js1959t13.aif; 13 sound files: high-resolution files, digital (.aif)
      "The Next Market Day" 00:02:27
      "The Coo Coo Bird" 00:02:00
      "Come A Tinker Or A Tailor" 00:02:40
      "Where Does It Lead" 00:00:51